Guide to the Frank J. Taylor Papers, 1928-1967
Department of Special Collections
Frank J. Taylor Papers,
1928-1967
Special Collections M0222
Taylor, Frank J., 1894-1972.
30 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted access: requires 24 hr. paging period.
Provenance
Gift of F. J. Taylor, 1968-1971.
Biographical Note
Frank J. Taylor, a prolific free-lance magazine writer, attended Stanford University. He worked as a newspaperman and covered WW I as a correspondent for United Press. In 1929 his career as a magazine writer began. He also published several historical works and a biography. He died October 23, 1972.
Scope and Content
Includes notes, research material, correspondence, articles, worksheets, drafts, and copies of Taylor's magazine articles for Saturday Evening Post, Reader's Digest, Country Gentlemen, and Collier's. Major subjects include agriculture, gardening, aviation, personalities, foreign countries, Stanford University, and various industrial topics. Also included are notes, research material, and drafts of some of Taylor's books, including SOUTHERN PACIFIC and BLACK BONANZA.
Container List
- ARTICLES, TEAR SHEETS AND A
  - Tear Sheets
    - Guys and Gals, Personalities and Profiles (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aviation Stories (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Bee Business (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The California Scene (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Farming Stories, Country Gent.--S.E.P.--RD (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fishing Stories (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Flower Business (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Food Stories (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hawaii Stories (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sports Stories (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Me and My Funny Foibles (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Working on the Railroad (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A--Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albright Story, RD, '65 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albright, How We Saved the Bug Trees (collaboration), S.E.P. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Accent--Tony Bishop, To Make Your Food Tastier, RD Oct. '55 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agriculture--California (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Agriculture, We Collect People on this Farm, C.G., Kermit Wilson, Oct. 1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Agriculture, He's Beating Summer Droughts, Carolina Rainmaker from California, C.G., W. B. Camp, July 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Agriculture, Darndest Farm You Ever Saw, Shell Oil Experimental Farm, C.G., March 1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Agriculture, Hybrid Vigor Comes to Vegetables, C.G. Feb. '45 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Agriculture, Farmers New Voice in Washington, A. J. McFadden, C.G., Jan. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Agriculture, Springboard to Farm Ownership (with Dr. Stanley B. Freeborn), (Davis Graduates), C.G. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Asgrow, Associated Seed Growers, Inc. (Story never Published) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Aviation--Airline Radar, RD (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Aviation (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Aviation--Psycho-Screening (RD) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Aviation--AiResearch, Cliff Garrett, RD '63 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Aviation--Gros. Brothers, Lockheed (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Aviation--Jatos Get 'Em Up, S.E.P. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Aviation--You'll Fly High, Wide, and Handsome, Pressure Pattern Flying, RD, Aug., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Airliner, That Wondrous Vehicle The Airliner, Dec. 1956, R.D., Modern Airlines (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Aviation, We Shoot Shadows, 8/26/44, S.E.P. (Night Flyers) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Air Transport--Jetliners, R.D. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- ARTICLES, A-C
  - Airport Story, R.D., #1, '64 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Airport Story #2, Dulles--Toronto--Honolulu Airports, R.D. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Airports, London-Paris-Vienna (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Airports, LA-SF-Chicago-N.Y. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Arizona Water Story (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Astronomy, Explorer of Outer Space, Magellan of the Starry Heavens, Dr. Humason, R.D. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Birds of Paradise (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bowron, The Bellicose Mayor, Mayor Bowron, S.E.P. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Broadmoor, Spencer Penrose Turned Gold and Copper into Colorado Beauty, 12/50 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Harry Whitcombe's Businesslike Bees, R.D., July 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Burpee, David (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Amazing Blossoms of Grandma Briggs, S.E.P., 9/27/52 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Please Send Buffalo--No Bull, 10/33 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - C--Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - The Many Californias - Travelogue, Californias Grapes of Wrath, Feb. 1952, R.D. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cement Story, RD (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - It Costs $1000 to Have Lunch with Harry Chandler, S.E.P., 12/16/39 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cheese - Colliers (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Chinatown (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Slum that Rebelled, The Shanty Town That Found Itself, S.E.P., Apr. 21, 1956, Casa Blanca - Riverside (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - California Physicians Service (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Chemicals on the Farm, Chemicals: The Farmer's New Hired Hand, C.G., West Coast Experiments (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Clothes, The Coldfire Boys, Gantron, S.E.P., 1/1/49 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Champion Jersey Dairyman, C.G., Ralph Cope (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Rubberneck Restaurant, The Man with Four Brown Derbies, Bob Cobb, S.E.P., 10/18/52 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Columbia Basin (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Cotton, King Cotton of California, W. B. Camp & G. J. Harrison, C.G. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Wizard of the Vegetable Patch, Frank Cuthbertson, R.D. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Father Crowley (Box 3, Folder 29)
- ARTICLES, C-F
  - D--Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Danes (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Data International - R.D. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Death Valley (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - DeGraff - Lilies (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hawaii's Indefatigable Land Maker, Walter Dillingham, R.D. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Drive In Movies, They Bet and Won on Ozone Cinema, Sept. 15, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A Bloom for Mother-In-Law, Dutch Bulb Industry, S.E.P., Apr. 13, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dwarf Trees (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Those Homemade Apple Trees, S.E.P. 2/27/54, Swarf Apples, Paul Stark (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Earthquake Sleuthe, R.D. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Earthchanger No. 1, Harry Morrison (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Earthworm Man - Thos. J. Barrett (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Garden of Fun, Elitch Gardens, S.E.P., 6/11/55 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - F--Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fargo Company (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mr. Ferry and Mr. Morse, Apr. 9, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Flowers - We Beat the Dutch, 5/12/45, Colliers (Folder 18, Box 3)
  - There's No Other Flower Shop Like This One, Flower Merchant Number One, Podesta Baldocchi - Goeppner, S.E.P. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Flowers - The Flowers Fly East, McClellan Bros., S.E.P., 8/7/48 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Flowers - They've Grown Some New Posies For the Ladies, Burpee Zinnias, etc., S.E.P. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Flowers - The Thirty-Million-Dollar-Flower, (Bulb Boom), S.E.P., 10/26/46 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Flowers (How Your Flowers Are Re-Modeled), Flowers are Ornery Critters, (New Flowers, S.E.P.), 3/1/47 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Flowers - Geranium Craze, S.E.P., 10/10/53 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Flowers, The Great Carnation Lottery, Denver Growers, S.E.P., 10/9/54 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Flowers, See What They're Doing to Lilies, Jan DeGraff, S.E.P., 10/15/49 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Whole Blooming Valley, Puyallup Bulb Festival, Colliers, Apr. 11, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Flowers - The Great Rose Lottery, Jackson & Perkins Story, S.E.P. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Flowers, Roses of Britain, R.D. '66 (Box 3, Folder 28a)
  - Flowers - Angels with Green Thumbs, L.A. Men's Garden Club, S.E.P. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Flowers - World's Most Colorful Club, They Like to Build Mountains, Oakland Spring Garden Show, S.E.P., 10/28/50 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Want to Borrow a Pet, John Forbes, Junior Museum, S.E.P., 6/26/54 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Foothill College, R.D. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The World's Worst Traffic Tangle, L.A. Freeway, S.E.P., 3/13/54 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- ARTICLES, G-H
  - Gardening Stories (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Beating Garden Pests (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Revolution in the Garden, Seeds, RD (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rushbutton Gardening, S.E.P. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gibeon, Lost City Found by Pritchard, S.E.P. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gold (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Golden Gate Bridge - Joseph Strauss, S.E.P. and RD (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Grand Teton (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mr. Gump of Gump's (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hawaii--Miscellaneous Material (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hawaii - Miscellaneous Assignments (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hawaii - Miscellaneous Booklets, Maps (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hawaii, Holiday Story (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hawaii, Look! Dancing the Hula!, Lurline-Howard K. Morris, S.E.P. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hawaii, Rev. Akaka, S.E.P. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Hawaii, Trip of 1957, U. of H. Story (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Happy Songwriters of Hawaii, S.E.P., 8/22/53 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hawaii, 1959, What a Boom Does to Paradise (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hawaii, Hawaii's Agricultural Magicians, Nations Business (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hawaii Since Statehood, '62 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hawaii Calls, Web Edwards (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hawaii: Jim Does's Dream - Pineapple, RD (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Holly Story (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Hearst Castle (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Hillercopters, What Makes Stanley Hiller Tick, Jan. 1948 & Daring Young Man on the Flying Windmill, Stanley Hiller, S.E.P., 6/28/52 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Duncan Hines (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hong Kong, Hole in the Bamboo Curtain, Armchair Travelogue, R.D. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Herbert Hoover International Detective, War Library, See Stanford--Hoover Library (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Short Cut to Good Will, Tom Davis, International Hospital Center, Nov. '56, RD
  - Humm, Psychologist to Joe and Jane Doakes, RD (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - He Sells Houses to Stars, Hollywood Homes, S.E.P., 7/25/53 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hotrod Club - Peterson (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hydroponics (Box 4, Folder 32)
- ARTICLES, I-L
  - I--Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Insurance Story (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Interflora, RD 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Jantzen, Give Youth a Chance, Zehntbauer - Jantzen, RD (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Japanese: Evacuation for S.E.P., Relocation for Colliers (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Japan's Fabulous Newspapers and Yukio Ozaki (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Japan, Imperial Hotel (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - They Ride the World's Mightest Tailwind, Pan-Am Jet Stream RD (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jet Turbine Locomotive, Casey Jones and the Big Blow, Feb. 1950, RD (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Jordan, David Starr, American Jan. '29 and R.D., Unforgettable May '63 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kern County - Everybody's Hospital, RD (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Henry J. Kaiser - biography (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Kado - Wizard of Rocks, S.E.P. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - What the World Owes to the Gardens of Kew, RD, 1/57 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Knight, Gov. Goodwin J., How to be a Success in Politics (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Farming with Two Hundred Partners, Kern Co. Land Company, Nat. Bus. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - He's a Sucker for Nasty Jobs, Killion-APL, SEP (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Klystron (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - KQED, SEP, 12/10/61 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Knott Berry Farm, Freedom Center (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - L--Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Life Series (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Laguna Art Festival, SEP (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Latin American Trip (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Latin America's Big Voice, Pan-American, July 1944, RD (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - He Sets the Sky on Fire, Fireworks, Lizza Loves to Light the Sky, SEP, 10/13/51 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Roughneck Boss of the Sailor's Union, Harry Lundeberg, SEP (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - The Town with Too Much Money, Long Beach, Frosty Martin, Long Beach, SEP (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - L.A. Police Rehab Center (Box 5, Folder 29)
- ARTICLES, M-P
  - M--Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Macadamia Story, 1962, RD (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Magic with `Mums, RD, '66 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - McLaren, John - Unforgettable, '55 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - George Mardikian, The GI's Chow Champion, RD (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Crazy over Ships, Kortum-Maritime Museum, Colliers (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Medicare, The Friendly Man from Medicare, RD, '66 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Million Dollar Music Box, Mattel, SEP, 12/6/52 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Strenuous Boss of Matson Navigation, Joe Sevier - Matson Nat. Bus., Apr. 1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mobile Home Living, The Lure of Living on Wheels, RD (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mormon Youth, RD, '61 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mormon Story - Bishops Storehouse, SEP (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - N--Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - National Parks (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Numbers - Call Me 522... RD 6/63 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Olive Story (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Oil Hunt, SEP & RD (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Oil, Cuyama Field, Excitement in Clamshell Valley, Cities Service, Jan. 1949 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Oil, Colorado's Fabulous Mountains of Oil, Shale Oil, RD (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Oranges - Sunkist Men (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Orchids - SEP, Sam Mosher (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Parker, Willis (His Best Friends Are Beasts) SEP (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Those High Jinks in Hollywood Pools, Paddock Pools - Phil Ilsley, SEP, 8/11/51 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Pacific Area War Correspondent, Nimitz-Kenney-Iwo Jima, RD (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Backstage at the Rose Parade, Tournament of Roses, SEP, 12/29/56 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - He Gambled on Flying and Won, W. A. Patterson, SEP & RD, 6/7/52 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - I've Got the Craziest Job!, Russ Pettit, SEP, 9/11/54 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Piggyback Railroading, SEP, 8/23/55 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - L. A. Police, How to Catch Crooks, RD, '53 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Portland's Teen-Age Hospital Wing, SEP (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Pottery, Dining off the Rainbow, Colored Dinnerware, SEP, 11/19/49 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- ARTICLES, R-S
  - R--Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Rainmakers, They Make Rain When Clouds Roll By, Dr. Irving Krick, Aug. 1954, RD (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Rain, Rearranging the Rain, June 1948, CG (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reber, They Want to Rebuild San Francisco Bay, Biggest Geography Job on Earth, John Reber, SEP, 11/18/50 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Frank Reinelt & His Tuberous Begonias (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Conservatism (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - S--Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - San Francisco, Holiday, July 1948 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Scotia, Paradise with a Waiting List, SEP, 2/21/51 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Death Valley Scotty (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Seattle Cent. 21 Expo (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Shopsmith, The Easy Way to Get Rick, How to Invent a Million Dollar Gadget, SEP, 3/29/52 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Shooting, Colliers, 8/3/35 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Southern Pacific, Battle of the Hotshots, SEP; Brother, Can You Spare a Locomotive, SEP; Fine Way to Run a Railroad, SEP & RD; Piggyback, SEP; and Look Story (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Siskiyou Murder - Southern Pacific (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Santa Fe Spud Special (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Snowshoe Thompson, RD (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Mr. Spice Islands (Frederic Johnson) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sugar (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Snake River Trout Ranch - Bob Erkins (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Stanford in Germany (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Stanford - Hoover Library (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Stanford (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Sterling - Stanford, SEP (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Switzerland, RD Overseas editions, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- ARTICLES, T-Z
  - Lifeline Under the Atlantic, Trans-Atlantic Cable, RD (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wonders of Direct Distance Dialing, Telephones, Long Distance Dialing, Oct. 55, RD (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Tex Taylor Ghosted Story ofr SEP (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Tent Biz, Boom in Big Tops, SEP (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Don Thomas, Booster #1 SEP (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Tomato Story, SEP (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - California's Wackiest Toy Merchant, Uncle Bernie, SEP (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Trees Can't Fight Back, Me and My Mixed-up Trees, SEP (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Trona, World's Biggest Mineral Stockpile, SEP, 3/5/49 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Truck Driving, Detour for Highway Mishaps, Safe Driving Clinic, Colliers (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Fishing, Tuna Jackpot, Tuna Industry, SEP, Apr. 10, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Turnbow - Foremost Wizard of Milk, RD, 6/30/59 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Alaska - Seward's Fortunate Folly, A Turning Point in History, RD (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Union that Prospers by Building Up the Boss, RD (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Unions, How Harry Bridges Rules the Pacific, Look, Water-front - Hawaii, 5/9/50 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Union Square Garage, $1,500,000 Parking Space, Andrew Pansini, Nat. Bus., Aug., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - University of California for RD (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - I Started Over at 62, Paulsen Visel, SEP, 7/21/51 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Walking Streets, RD (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Warren Family vs. Polio, Honeybear's Miracle, RD (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Earl Warren Stories for SEP (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Water Sports (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Weather Stories (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - California Moves the Rain, In California Moving the Rain is Big Business, Water Transport, Nat Bus, Aug 1952 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Water Story - CG (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Wells Fargo, Wild West Bank, History Room, SEP, 6/17/50 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Wilderness Cave for Delinquints, 12/4/54, SEP, Juvenile Rehabilitation (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Widow Story, RD. See also File No. 12, Folder 11--Research Material on a planned but never published handbook on how to be a widow (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - I Work on the Railroad and How!, Zephyrette Story, SEP, 1/7/56 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Swapping Zoo Keepers, Animal Trading at Zoos, SEP, 2/11/56 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- BOOKS: SOUTHERN PACIFIC, DEMOCRACY'S AIR ARSENAL, AND HIGH HORIZONS
  - Why Write Books?, A memo for Professor Rivers (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Southern Pacific, by Neill C. Wilson and Frank J. Taylor (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - The story behind Southern Pacific, Correspondence and A memo on Southern Pacific (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Four Iron-Horse Men, two manuscripts by Frank J. Taylor (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Material for the Huntington Book:, Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Photographs (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Material for the Huntington Book: Correspondence, Notes, and a copy of the article The Romance that Founded Stanford, by G. T. Clark (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Typewritten Notes: The Voyage of the Old Ship Humboldt, Newspaper Articles, Correspondence of Stanford and Huntington, and Press Comments on the Stanford Huntington Quarrel (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Type-written Notes: Various Biographical Sketches of Collis P. Huntington, Material Copied from Archer Huntington's scrapbook, and notes from Charles Crocker, Chronicles of the Builders of the Commonwealth (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - More Type-written Notes: Notes made after a conversation with W. H. Mills: with the purpose of Preserving Mill's ideas, Notes on newspaper articles, and an autobiographical statement by Collis P. Huntington (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - From Trail to Rail, Tear Sheets from the Southern Pacific Bulletin (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Democracy's Air Arsenal, by Frank J. Taylor and Lawton Wrigh (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Democracy's Air Arsenal, a memo by Frank J. Taylor (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Democracy's Air Arsenal, Correspondence & Contracts (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Publisher's Draft of Democracy's Air Arsenal (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Final Draft, Democracy's Air Arsenal, and suggestions for improvement by William F. Peters (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Pat Paterson, a book by Frank J. Taylor (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - High Horizons, by Frank J. Taylor, New Revised Edition, 1964 (paperback) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - High Horizons, by Frank J. Taylor, New Revised Edition, 1964 (hardbound) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - High Horizons, by Frank J. Taylor, 1958 edition, marked copy (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - High Horizons, by Frank J. Taylor, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- BOOKS: HIGH HORIZONS (cont.) & PAT PATTERSON
  - High Horizons, United Air Lines History, By Frank Taylor
    - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1963 Revision--Correspondence, Research Material, and Drafts (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Acknowledgement of Receipts (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Revision 1964--Correspondence, Research Material, and Drafts (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1963 Revision--Research Material (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1957 Revision--Drafts and Notes (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1954 Revision--Drafts and Notes (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Dawn to Dusk and Miscellaneous United Air Lines Data (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Magazines and Miscellaneous Research Material (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - The Pratt & Whitney Aircraft Story, a book (no author given) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Pat Patterson--1967--For United Air Lines
    - Corrections for Final Draft of Patterson Book (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Early Drafts of Pat Patterson Profile (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Pat Patterson Quotes for the book (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Duplicates of Interviews (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Rough Draft of People Make an Airline (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Intermediate Draft, Pat Patterson Profile, folders one and two (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
    - Author's mss. submitted to United Executives (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Pat Patterson, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Patterson Book Reference Material (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Interviews for Patterson Book (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Pat Patterson Interviews (Box 10, Folder 22)
- BOOKS: THE 76 BONANZA, THE BLACK BONANZA, AND COPIES OF MISCELLANEOUS FARLY WRITINGS
  - The 76 Bonanza, the Fabulous Life and Times of the Union Oil Company of California, by Earl M. Welty and Frank J. Taylor, 1966, sequel and revision of The Black Bonanza (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Black Bonanza, by Earl M. Welty and Frank J. Taylor, Second Revised Edition, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Black Bonanza, 1950, by Earl M. Welty and Frank J. Taylor (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The story behind The Black Bonanza and The 76 Bonanza, a memo; also Correspondence re: (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - 76 Bonanza, '65 Revision: Research Material, Articles, and Manuscript (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 76 Bonanza, '65 Revision: Notes and Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Big Business is Good for Little Business--and Vice Versa, an article by Frank J. Taylor and Earl M. Welty (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Black Bonanza--First Revision, Original Manuscript (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - The Black Bonanza, 1956 Revision, Final Manuscript (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - The Black Bonanza, More Revision Material (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The Black Bonanza, Articles and Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Magazines, magazine articles, and annual reports from Oil Companies (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Oh, Ranger! a book about the National Parks, by Horace M. Albright and Frank J. Taylor, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Land of Homes, a book about California, by F. J. Taylor, 192 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Grand Canyon Country, by Frank J. Taylor, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Pop Warner's Book for Boys, by Glenn S. Pop Warner with Frank J. Taylor, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Our U.S.A., A Gay Geography, Text by Frank J. Taylor, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- BOOKS: BRO. CASTLE & BRO. COOKE
  - A memo on Bro. Castle & Bro. Cooke, an unpublished company history (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Castle & Cooke Book--Correspondence and Notes (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Bro. Castle & Bro. Cooke, by Frank J. Taylor and Neill C. Wilson, complete manuscript, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bro. Castle & Bro. Cooke, an incomplete manuscript copy partially edited (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Bro. Castle & Bro. Cooke, Office Copy, Complete Manuscript (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Castle and Cooke, Research Materials and Notes (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Research Material and Notes on Hawaii (Box 12, Folder 7)